(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-06T01:51:02.151928",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.6-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
ときのそら 生誕祭 2025
Tokino Sora Birthday Party 2025
われらの空の始まりは
Our sky's beginning...
触れた瞬間 アララララ
The moment we touched, oh dear!
あーこれは困った
Ah, this is a problem,
二度と元に戻らない大爆発
a big explosion that can never be undone!
そして星が生まれまして
And so a star was born,
明け方の一番星は
and the morning's first star...
あなたと出会った
met with you!
これは次元を揺るがす大発見
This is a dimension-shaking discovery!
このままハート打ち上げて
Launching my heart just like this,
どこまでも高い空までめっちゃ飛んじゃいたい
I want to fly super high into the sky!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that went star-star-start,
あなたがいなきゃ今頃超新星してるぞ
without you, it'd be going supernova right now!
申請中！
"Application in progress!"
あなたに言ってます
I'm talking to you!
スタースタースタートなのは分かってる
I know it's a star-star-start,
ほら目の前にずっとある一等星見てろ
look at the first-magnitude star right in front of you!
見てろ！
"Keep looking!"
このビッグバン気づいて
Notice this Big Bang!
あいまいちゅうくらいにふくらんでこんなになってんぞ
Swell up vaguely to medium size and look what it's become!
そうそう大体の惑星はこのときのためのスター
That's right, most planets are stars just for this moment!
テテテテ低浮上だし
T-t-t-t-low activity,
あなたのハートにノーティス
notice in your heart!
ヒマなときでいいよみたいな顔してめっちゃめっちゃ待機
Act like "whenever you're free is fine" while waiting super eagerly!
ちょっとの反応くれたら喜ぶし
If you give even a little reaction, I'll be thrilled,
てかこんなのを逃すなんて嘆かわしい
besides, missing out on this would be so deplorable!
我らの星の活動は
Our star's activities...
割と続いていても
Even if they continue quite a bit...
いやーこれはすごいな
Wow, this is amazing!
つまりあなたと私の創世記
In short, it's the genesis of you and me!
このままハートあなたごと連れて
Taking my heart along with you just like this,
彼方を目指してめっちゃ飛んじゃった
aiming for beyond, I flew super far!
スタースタースタートしたこのラブは
This love that went star-star-start,
あなたがいなきゃ今頃超新星してた
without you, it would've gone supernova by now!
してた！
"It would've!"
ほら今日まで続いた
Look, it's continued all the way until today!
あんたスタースタースタートちゃんと分かってね
Make sure you properly understand the star-star-start!
一層眩しく輝く一等星
A first-magnitude star shining even brighter!
あなたと！
"With you!"
私で！
"And me!"
ビッグバンしたいの！
I want to make a Big Bang!
あいまいちゅうくらいにふくらんでこんなになってんぞ
Swell up vaguely to medium size and look what it's become!
そうそう大体の惑星はこのときのためにさ
That's right, most planets are for this moment...
みんなー！
Everyone!
今日は、お誕生日ライブに来てくれて、ありがとうー！
Thank you so much for coming to my birthday live today!
最初に聴いてもらったのは、『スタースタースタート』でしたー！
The first song you listened to was "Star Star Start"!
みんなコメント見えてるよ！初めましての人もいっぱいコメントしてってね！
I see everyone's comments! First-timers, please leave lots of comments too!
えー、最初から…すごい…気合を入れすぎましたね！
Um, right from the start... wow... I put way too much energy into it, didn't I?
というわけで、えー、今日は私のお誕生日です！
So anyway, um, today is my birthday!
喉が渇きました。お水失礼します。
My throat got dry. Excuse me while I grab some water.
ん？味が違う！おいしい！
Huh? The taste is different! It's delicious!
はい！というわけで、お水おいしいじゃ…というわけで、今日のハッシュタグは、
Alright! So, "water is delicious"... anyway, today's hashtag is...
ときのお披露目生誕祭2025です！
#TokinoRevealBirthday2025!
ぜひトレンドにも入れたいので、よければそちらでも呟いてください！
We really want to get it trending, so please tweet with it if you can!
そしてですね、新衣装のお披露目や、ゲストをたくさん呼んでいるので、
And also, we have new outfit reveals and lots of guests coming,
楽しみにしててね！
so please look forward to it!
というわけで、今回はね、カウントダウンでも使われているアリーナに、私の装飾をしてもらいました！
So this time, the arena that was also used for the countdown was decorated for me!
どーお？可愛いでしょー！
How is it? Isn't it super cute?!
そして、見て！ぬんぬんがね…
And look! Nun-nun is...
4段になってるんです
It's stacked four layers high now.
4段になってるのは、あの...
The reason it's four layers is...
毎年増やしてるから4段なんですね
because we add one every year, so it's four layers.
てことは来年は5段になるんだな
Which means next year it'll be five layers.
すごい、どんどん積まれていっちゃうね
Wow, they just keep stacking up higher and higher.
そして、あんきももですね、今回はホログラムでビッグサイズ！
And Ankimo is a hologram this time, in a super big size!
でか！
Huge!
本当に大きい
It's really big.
私だけを映すと文字しか映らないっていうビッグサイズなんですよね
When the camera focuses on me, you can only see the text on him—that's how big he is.
お団子かな？そう、お団子なんですよ
Is it a dango? Yeah, it's a dango!
ぬんぬんそうでしょ？
Right, Nun-nun?
ちょっとね、でも怖...
It's a bit scary though...
顔がね、大きくて見えないので
His face is so big that you can't see it, so...
あ！じゃあ、ぬんぬーん！
Ah! Then, Nun-nuuun!
来る？
Is he coming?
あ！来たー！ぬんぬんが来ました！
Ah, he's here! Nun-nun has arrived!
というわけで、ぬんぬん乗せてもらってもいいかな？
So then, Nun-nun, can I ride on you?
いい？
Is it okay?
うわー！
Woah!
埋まってるけどね、乗るっていうより
I'm kind of sinking into it rather than riding, though!
はーい！
Yay!
ということで、こちらがあんきもの顔です
So anyway, this right here is Ankimo's face.
あんきもはずっとこうやって動いてます
Ankimo keeps moving like this the whole time.
そして、意外とねつぶらな瞳なんですけど、ちゅちゅちゅってしっかりね、お目目になってるんですね
And despite having surprisingly bead-like eyes, they're drawn so clear and cute.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
うん、うん、うん、うん
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.
そして、お！みーんなー！見えてるよー！
And oh! Everyone! I can see you!
会場のみんなー！ありがとう！
Everyone in the venue! Thank you!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
見えてるぞー！
I can see you!
はーい！
Yay!
うおー！すごい！
Woah! Amazing!
ぬんぬんが空を飛ばせてくれました！
Nun-nun let me fly in the sky!
イェーイ！
Yay!
というわけで、そんなぬんぬんが降ろしてくれた場所はさっきと違う場所ですね
So anyway, the place Nun-nun set me down is a different spot from earlier.
もう1回お水を飲んだら曲に行きたいかなと思います
After taking another sip of water, I think I'd like to move on to the songs.
いやー、今日はね、ドキドキなんですよ
Man, I'm so nervous today.
生放送ってね、やっぱドキドキしますよね
Live broadcasts really get your heart racing, don't they?
なんか分かる？さっきまでね、「調子悪い調子悪い」って言ってたのにね、今全然調子悪くなくなっちゃった
You know? Up until a moment ago I was saying "I feel under the weather," but now I feel completely fine.
こんなだから誰にも心配してもらえないんだ
Because I'm like this, nobody ever worries about me!
というわけで、次の曲言ってみましょう
Anyway, let's head to the next song.
2曲続けて聴いてください
Please listen to the next two songs back-to-back.
喜びが舞う 春を
Spring, where joy dances...
涙の羽
Wings of tears...
散りゆく花びらとなり
Becoming falling flower petals,
あなたの元へと
heading toward where you are.
風が鳴るたび
Whenever the wind rustles,
そばにいるよ たどり着ける
I'll be by your side, I can reach you.
悲しみより 寂しさより
More than sadness, more than loneliness,
守るべきを 今を生きる
what must be protected, living in the present.
あなた 生まれ変わったら 桜の下で また会いましょう
If you are reborn, let us meet again beneath the cherry blossoms.
きっとその時には 笑い合って 永遠を誓おう
Surely when that time comes, we will smile together and vow eternity.
愛し愛されて この命は 芽吹いて咲いて
Loving and being loved, this life buds and blooms.
色褪せない眼差しを胸に 毎日祈る
Holding your unfading gaze in my heart, I pray every day.
ああ あなたに ああ あなたに ああ あなたに 抱かれて
Ah, held by you... Ah, held by you... Ah, held in your arms...
降り注ぐ雨 音やむ
The pouring rain... its sound ceases.
まだ
Still,
光はなく
there is no light...
右と左の
The wings on my right
翼は
and left
きつく揺れてる
are swaying violently.
穏やかな日々
While believing in
信じながら
peaceful days,
愛してると
wanting to tell you
伝えたくて
that I love you...
伝えないのは
Not telling you is because
忘れてほしい
I want you to forget me,
明日を生きて行くため
so you can go on living tomorrow.
生まれ変わったら
If we are reborn,
桜の下で
beneath the cherry blossoms,
また会いましょう
let us meet again.
待ち焦がれた季節の中で
In the season we've longed for,
ともに歩こう
let's walk together.
この心を染めた花よ
Oh, flower that dyed this heart,
あなたに届け
reach out to you,
誇り高き愛を乗せて
carrying a proud love,
名もなき風に
upon a nameless wind.
大切なものは いつの時代も
The things that matter most, no matter the era,
変わらないこと
never change.
人は知りながら
Though people know this,
過ちを
why do they keep repeating
なぜ繰り返す
their mistakes?
生まれ変わったら
If we are reborn,
桜の下で
beneath the cherry blossoms,
また会いましょう
let us meet again.
きっとそのときには笑って
Surely then, with a smile,
永遠を誓おう
let's vow eternity.
愛し愛されてこの命は
Loving and being loved, this life
芽吹いて咲いて
sprouts and blooms.
色褪せない眼差しを胸に
Holding an unfading gaze in my heart,
舞い散る願い
my wishes scatter like petals.
ああ あなたに
Ah, to you,
ah, to you,
ああ あなたに
伝えたい
I want to convey it...
ああ あなたに
Ah, to you,
ah, to you,
ああ あなたに
伝えたい
I want to convey it...
命に嫌われている。
[Hated by Life Itself.]
「死にたい」なんて言うなよ
"I want to die," don't say things like that.
諦めないで生きろよ
"Don't give up, keep living,"
そんな歌が正しいなんてバカげてるよな
saying a song like that is right is ridiculous, isn't it?
実際自分は死んでもよくて
In truth, I don't care if I die,
周りが死んだら悲しくて
but if those around me died, I'd be sad.
それが嫌だからっていうエゴなんです
It's just the ego of "I don't want that."
他人が生きていてもどうでもよくて
I couldn't care less if others live,
誰かを嫌うこともファッションで
and disliking someone is just a fashion statement.
それでも平和に生きようなんて素敵なことでしょう
But even so, "Let's live in peace," isn't that wonderful?
画面の先では誰かが死んで
On the other side of the screen, someone dies,
それを嘆いて誰かが歌って
someone mourns it and sings a song,
それに感化された少年が
and influenced by that, a boy
ナイフを持って走った
ran off holding a knife.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself,
価値観もエゴも押し付けて
forcing our values and egos onto others.
いつも誰かを殺したい歌を
Always broadcasting songs that want to kill someone
簡単電波で流した
easily over the airwaves.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself,
軽々しく「死にたい」だとか
casually saying "I want to die,"
軽々しく命を見てる
looking at life so carelessly,
僕らは命に嫌われている
we are hated by life itself.
お金がないので今日も
Having no money, today again
1日中惰眠を貪る
I indulge in sleeping all day long.
生きる意味なんて見出せず
Unable to find any meaning in living,
無駄を自覚して息をする
I breathe, fully aware of my worthlessness.
言葉でこの傷が表せていいものか
Could these words ever truly express this pain?
そんな事ばかり抱え 今日も一人ベッドに眠る
Saddled with thoughts like that, I sleep alone in bed again today.
少年だった僕たちは いつか青年に変わっていく
We who were once boys will turn into young men someday.
年老いていつか枯れ葉のように 誰にも知られず朽ちていく
Growing old, we'll decay like withered leaves without anyone ever knowing.
不死身の身体を手に入れて 一生死なずに生きていく
Obtaining an immortal body, living on forever without ever dying.
そんなSFを妄想してる
I keep daydreaming about sci-fi fantasies like that.
自分が死んでもどうでもよくて
I don't care if I die,
それでも周りに生きて欲しくて 矛盾を抱えて生きてくなんて怒られてしまう
yet I want those around me to live—I'll get scolded for living with such contradictions.
「正しいものは正しくいなさい」
"Those who are right must act properly."
「死にたくないなら生きていなさい」
"If you don't want to die, then go on living."
悲しくなるならそれでもいいなら ずっと一人で笑えよ
If you're going to be sad, if you're okay with that, then laugh alone forever.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福の意味すらわからず
Without even understanding the meaning of happiness,
生まれた環境ばかり憎んで
hating nothing but the circumstances of our birth,
簡単に過去ばかり呪う
so easily cursing nothing but our past.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
サヨナラばかりが多すぎて
Having said far too many goodbyes,
本当の別れを知らない
without ever knowing a true farewell.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福も 別れも 愛情も 友情も
Happiness, farewells, affection, friendship...
滑稽な夢の戯れで
all foolish playful dreams,
全部金で買える品物
goods that can all be bought with money.
明日死んでしまうかもしれない
I might die tomorrow.
すべて無駄になるかもしれない
Everything might turn out to be pointless.
朝も夜も春も秋も 変わらず誰かがどこかで死ぬ
Morning, night, spring, autumn—without change, someone dies somewhere.
夢も明日も何もいらない
I don't need dreams, tomorrow, or anything else.
君が生きていたならそれでいっそいい
If you are alive, that's all I could ever ask for.
本当は そういうことが歌いたい
Honestly, those are the kinds of things I want to sing about.
命に嫌われている
Hated by life itself.
結局いつかは死んでいく
In the end, everyone dies someday.
君だって僕だっていつかは 枯れ葉のように朽ちてく
You and I will both decay like withered leaves someday.
それでも僕らは必死に生きて
Even so, we desperately live,
命を必死に抱えて生きて
desperately clinging onto our lives,
殺してあがいて笑って抱えて
killing, struggling, laughing, holding on,
生きて、生きて、生きて、生きて、生きろ。
living, living, living, living, live.
はい！ということで今聴いてもらったのは『桜旅』と『命に嫌われている。』でした！
Alright! So those two songs you just heard were "Sakuratabi" and "Hated by Life itself"!
わー、緊張しすぎてちょっと何回かどもっちゃった…
Wow, I was so nervous that I stumbled over my words a few times...
リハのほうが声出てたよ絶対に。ね？そうでしょう？カメラさん…え？
My voice definitely came out better during rehearsal. Right? Don't you think, Mr. Cameraman? Huh?
わーい！今トレンド2位なの？みんなありがとう！
Yay! Is it trending at #2 right now? Thank you, everyone!
急なテンションの差にビビらないで！ねぇ？ねぇ？
Don't be startled by the sudden shift in mood! Okay? Okay?
めちゃめちゃよかった？「ワンコ」って言わないで！私犬じゃないんだ…ワン！
It was super good? Don't call me a puppy! I'm not a dog... Woof!
ありがとうございます！あ…これ美味しい！ありがとう！
Thank you so much! Ah... this is delicious! Thank you!
落差がすごい、ね？落差すごいよね！
The contrast is huge, right? Such a huge contrast!
いやぁ…でもさ、まだまだライブは始まったばかりだよ！
Man... But hey, the concert has only just begun!
今日初めて観に来ましたよーって人！ぜひ楽しんでってね！
For anyone who's watching for the first time today, please enjoy the show!
イェーイ！ご機嫌！
Yay! In a great mood!
というわけで、早速次はゲストパートに行っちゃおうかな！最初のゲストは、この人だ！
So with that, let me move right along to the guest segment! Our first guest is this person!
ゲスト：緋月ゆい
[Guest: Hizuki Yui]
はい！ということで最初のゲストは、ゆいちゃんです！ゆいちゃーん！
Alright! So our very first guest is Yui-chan! Yui-chan!
そらさん！
Sora-san!
ちょっと待って、声やばい！
Wait, my voice is terrible!
そらさん！声やば！
Sora-san! Your voice is terrible!
えぐい、えぐい声してる！
It sounds so rough!
お誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
すみません...もう本当にこの度は...
I'm so sorry... really, this time...
誠に誠に申し訳ございませんでした...
I am so, so terribly sorry...
ちょっと良くなってきた？
Has it gotten a bit better?
え？何ですか？
Eh? What is it?
ちょっと待って、声出ない！
Wait a second, my voice won't come out!
リハーサルの時の方が声出てた。何があったの？
My voice was better during rehearsal. What happened?
この数時間の間に何があったの？
What happened in these past few hours?
相当出にくさが出てるね。
It's really hard for you to speak right now.
お大事にね。
Take good care of yourself.
ね、ということでね、体調ね...
Right, so about your condition...
体調というか喉をね...
Well, not your condition, but your throat...
咳が止まらなくなってしまって...本当に申し訳ないです。
I couldn't stop coughing... I'm so terribly sorry.
こんな晴れ舞台にお誘いいただいたのに、本当に申し訳ないです。
Even though you invited me to such a grand stage, I'm so sorry.
本当は今日一緒に歌う予定だったんですけど...
Actually, we were planning to sing together today, but...
歌いたかった...
I wanted to sing...
次に歌う『限りなく灰色へ』という曲を歌おうと思ったんですけど...
We were going to sing "Kagirinaku Haiiro he" next, but...
練習したんです...
I even practiced...
去年3Dになったじゃん、ゆいちゃんが。
You got your 3D model last year, right, Yui-chan?
ずっと去年も呼ぼうと思ってたんだけど、去年はまだ3Dじゃなくって。
I wanted to invite you last year too, but you didn't have 3D yet.
歌を届けるからずっとコラボしたくて、今年の誕生日にはゆいちゃんを呼ぼうって決めて...
I always wanted to collab, so I decided to invite you for this year's birthday!
そんなに思っててくださったのに、私ったら！
You thought of me that much, and yet I...!
で、ゆいちゃんにも合いそうな曲と思って、この曲を選んだんですよね。
And I chose this song thinking it would really suit you.
私のために選んでくださったのに！何にしてんだ、馬鹿野郎！
Even though you picked it for me! What am I doing, foolish me!
でもこの状態で、お喋りだけでも出てくれるのはとっても嬉しいから！
But even like this, I'm so happy you came out just to talk!
むしろ、ただお喋りのために参加させていただいて、本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for letting me participate just for talking!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
だからさ、今度配信じゃなくて、動画とか一緒に作ったりしようか？
So, next time, instead of a stream, shall we make a video together?
歌ってみたとか。
Like a cover song.
今回のリベンジみたいな感じでさ。
Like a revenge match for this time.
ね？
Right?
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
やろう！
Let's do it!
やりたいです！
I want to do it!
やったー！
Yay!
みんなも見たいよねー！
Everyone wants to see it too, right?
ペチペチ音が聞こえる。
I hear slapping sounds.
頬っぺペチペチしてました。
I was slapping my cheeks.
そっちのペチペチか！こらっ、て。
Ah, that kind of slapping!
本当にこの出演ありがとうございます！嬉しい、本当に。
Thank you so much for appearing! I'm really glad.
もう歌が良すぎて、私、ゲスト出る前ちょっと感極まりそうだった...
The singing was so good that before coming out, I was almost moved to tears...
本当に？ありがとう！
Really? Thank you!
さっき歌われてた歌が良すぎて...
The song you sang earlier was so good...
あ、本当？
Ah, really?
感動しました。
I was deeply moved.
本番の方が良かったかな？
Was the live performance better?
もうめちゃくちゃ素敵でした！
It was insanely wonderful!
やったー、やったー！
Yay, yay!
次の曲、二人用なんですけど、一人で頑張って歌おうと思うので...
The next song was meant for two, but I'll do my best to sing it solo...
ぜひ、よろしく...
So please...
応援しています！
I'm cheering for you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張ってください。すみません、本当に。
Please do your best. I'm so sorry, truly.
いや全然！また一緒に遊ぼうね！
No, not at all! Let's hang out again!
はい、ぜひ！ありがとうございました、本当に！
Yes, absolutely! Thank you so much, really!
はい、というわけで、水樹ゆいちゃんでした！
Alright, that was Mizuki Yui-chan!
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
では、また一緒にね、話そうね！
Well then, let's talk together again!
はい、失礼します！
Yes, excuse me!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
頑張ってください！またねー！
Good luck! See you~
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
あ、消えちゃった...消えちゃった...
Ah, she disappeared... she disappeared...
というわけで、まさかの一人で歌います。聴いてください、『限りなく灰色へ』。
So, unexpectedly, I'll sing it solo. Please listen to "Kagirinaku Haiiro he".
限りなく灰色へ
[Title: Kagirinaku Haiiro he]
才能なんてないから
Because I have no talent,
ここで一生泣いているんだろう
I'll probably cry here for the rest of my life.
目に映った景色の青さが
The blueness of the scenery reflected in my eyes...
羨ましく思っていた
...made me feel so envious.
路傍に転がる人生
A life tumbling along the roadside,
アスファルトの温度下がってる
the asphalt's temperature is dropping.
真夜中を照らす明かりを求め
Seeking a light to illuminate the dead of night,
繋ぐ電波 世界へと
I connect radio waves into the wide world.
0に 0に 求めるものだけ描いた
Onto zero, onto zero, I drew only what I sought.
じっと孤独を奏でてる
Softly playing my solitude,
指先から伝わっていく
spreading from my fingertips,
無彩色の色
achromatic colors flow.
認めてはくれないの？
Won't you acknowledge me?
燻んでしまったの灰色に
It's all dulled into gray.
こんな才能なんて借り物
A talent like this is borrowed time;
まだ人生終わってないから
my life isn't over yet,
諦めるなって誰かの声
"Don't give up," says a distant voice.
見失ってしまったの灰色に
Lost within this gray...
気づけなくて今も抗ってる
Unable to realize it, I still resist.
この感情奪い去ってよ
Take this emotion away!
泥々になってしまう前に
Before I turn into complete mud...
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye to a world like this!
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting blurred feelings,
夢の形になっちゃった
it took the shape of my dreams.
いつかはできると思ってた
I thought I could do it someday,
だけど現実残酷だろ
but reality is cruel, isn't it?
焦りと不安の渦の間に
Amidst the whirlpool of anxiety and haste,
黒くなって浮かんでる
turning black, floating...
怠惰的なセンスと
With a decadent sense
曖昧な表現なんかじゃ
and vague expressions,
気を衒った奴らのあれこれに
affected show-offs with their trickery
飲み込まれて消えていく
swallow me up until I disappear.
レイニー レイニー 荒れ狂っていくドローイング
Rainy, rainy, wild drawings raging on,
肩を濡らして残った
leaving my shoulders soaked,
冷たい記憶の体温
the body heat of cold memories.
レイニー レイニー 雲の隙間から覗いた
Rainy, rainy, peeking through gaps in the clouds,
光当たって届いて
light struck and reached out,
体を軽くしたんだ
making my body feel lighter.
美学とか
Aesthetics,
プライドとか
pride,
語る前に
before speaking of those—
やれることやっていけ
Do what you can do!
嫉妬してしまったの怠惰に
Envying idleness,
焼け落ちた才能を1つ置いてけ
leave one burnt talent behind!
ただやったもん勝ちなん解でしょ
Isn't it first come, first served?
固唾飲んでる場合じゃないでしょ
It's no time to hold your breath!
目を開いても変わらぬ灰色に
Open your eyes, yet unchanged gray...
気づいたってどうしようもないから
Realizing it changes nothing,
それを虎視眈々と狙ってる
so I watch like a tiger seeking its prey,
ペルソナになって擦られないよ
becoming a persona, never to be worn down!
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye to a world like this!
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting blurred feelings,
言葉の意味飲み込んで
swallowing the meaning of words.
燻んでしまったの灰色に
It's all dulled into gray.
こんな才能なんて借り物
A talent like this is borrowed time;
まだ人生終わってないから
my life isn't over yet,
諦めるなって誰かの声
"Don't give up," says a distant voice.
見失ってしまったの灰色に
Lost within this gray...
気づけなくて今も抗ってる
Unable to realize it, I still resist.
この感情奪い去ってよ
Take this emotion away!
泥々になってしまう前に
Before I turn into complete mud...
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Goodbye, goodbye, goodbye to a world like this!
滲む思いなぞって描いた
Tracing and painting blurred feelings,
夢の形笑っていた
the shape of my dreams was smiling.
はい、皆さんありがとうございました！
Yes! Thank you so much, everyone!
一回一回お水飲まないと息が切れてしまいますね。
If I don't sip water every time, I'll run out of breath!
あにゃい… あにゃいじゃない！
Anyai... Wait, not "anyai"!
反応してしまった！「はい」って！
I actually responded! Saying "Yes!"
いやー、というわけでゲスト、まだまだ見たいよね？
Well then! You still want to see more guests, right?
ということでどんどん行っちゃいましょうか！
So, shall we keep right on going?
続いてのゲストはこの人です！
Our next guest is this person!
ゲスト 富士葵
[Guest: Fuji Aoi]
白い薔薇の花びら ひとつふたつ開けば
If one or two petals of a white rose bloom,
あの日の記憶 蘇るでしょう
memories of that day will surely awaken.
安らぎに照らされて 花を咲かせた夜は
On nights when flowers bloomed, illuminated by peace,
甘く切なく 色付いていく
they sweetly and painfully gather color.
光る糸をたどるように
Tracing the glowing thread,
時は静かに流れて
time flows quietly.
満ち引く揺らぎに沿いながら
Following the ebb and flow,
人は生まれ変わる
people are reborn.
あなたの微笑みは
Your smile is...
胸を溶かすぬくもり
...a warmth that melts my heart.
どこかで見た
Somewhere I've seen...
夢のような
a dream-like...
沈む夕日
setting sun.
今を切り取られても
Even if this moment is cut away,
二人の影は重なっていく
our two shadows overlap.
果てしなく遠く
Endlessly far,
限りなく深く
boundlessly deep,
交わった運命のように
like intersecting destinies.
何度重なって
Grasping time and time again,
何度も知らせて
losing time and time again,
やっと巡り逢えたこと
we finally found each other.
空が地を求め
The sky seeks the earth,
花が雨を待ち
the flower awaits the rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
the night begs for tomorrow.
二つの心が一つのこと
Two hearts becoming one,
こんなにも求めてたの
is what we've desired so deeply.
長い眠り解いて
Unraveling the long sleep,
今宵巡り逢えたら
if we meet again tonight,
二人のロンド さあ踊りましょう
let's dance our rondo.
過ぎ去った日々を流すように
As if washing away past days,
月は優しく揺れる
the moon sways gently.
記憶の先にもう一度
Once again, beyond memories,
愛しさが溢れた
fondness overflows.
あなたの年月を二重に
Overlapping your years
歩めるなら
if we can walk together,
陰とならせ
let me become the shade,
守っていたい
I want to protect you.
吹き迷う風が
Even if the straying wind
二人を遠ざけても
drives us apart,
信じることを忘れないで
never forget to believe.
褪せない煌めき
An unfading sparkle,
儚い揺らめき
a fleeting glimmer,
漂う幻のように
like a drifting phantom.
彷徨いながらも
Even while wandering,
変わらない場所へ
to an unchanging place,
やっと辿り着いたこと
we finally arrived.
闇が光を奪い
Darkness steals the light,
嘘が罪になり
lies become sin,
過去が未来を裂いても
and even if the past tears the future apart,
巡り行くように
As cycle after cycle moves,
きっとこの場所を
surely this place
私は選んでいたのだろう
is what I had chosen.
みんな盛り上がっていこうね！
Everyone, let's keep the hype going!
コメントもたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for all your comments!
果てしなく遠く
Endlessly far,
限りなく深く
boundlessly deep,
交わった運命のように
like intersecting destinies.
何度重なって
Grasping time and time again,
何度も知らせて
losing time and time again,
やっと巡り逢えたこと
we finally found each other.
空が地を求め
The sky seeks the earth,
花が雨を待ち
the flower awaits the rain,
夜が明日を乞うように
the night begs for tomorrow.
二つの心が一つのこと
Two hearts becoming one,
こんなにも求めてたの
is what we've desired so deeply.
白い薔薇の花びら 一つ二つ散るとき
When one or two white rose petals scatter,
優しい朝に染められるでしょう
they'll likely be dyed in the gentle morning light.
そして生まれ変わって
And being reborn,
あなたの胸に咲けば
if I bloom in your heart,
二人の愛は永遠になる
our love will become eternal.
はい！ということで...
Alright! And so...
2人目のゲストは、あおいちゃんだよー！
our second guest is Aoi-chan!
みなさん、富士葵です！こんばんは！
Everyone, I'm Fujii Aoi! Good evening!
富士葵です！
It's Fujii Aoi!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me!
いや、ずっと呼びたくて！ありがとう！
No, I've wanted to invite you for so long! Thank you!
なんかさ、コラボとかはしてるけど、こういう風に一緒にやるのは...
You know, we've done collabs, but doing something like this together is...
あれだよね、2年前の私の記念配信以来...
right, since my anniversary stream two years ago...
100万人の！
The 1-million sub stream!
そうそうそうそう！
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah!
だから、しかも2人で歌うのは相当久しぶりじゃない？
So, singing as a duo is super long overdue, right?
もっと前だよね！
It was even further back!
なつかしいって感じがする！
It really feels so nostalgic!
え、ちょっとさ、ネイル見せてよ！
Hey, show me your nails!
青です
It's blue!
紫です
It's purple!
頑張って塗ったよー
I worked hard painting them!
ねー！おしゃれしたよー！
Right? Got all dressed up!
見てー！
Look!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いやーあの、あんきももね、積み上がって... あんきもじゃないや、ぬんぬんね
Well, you know, Ankimo too, piling up... wait, not Ankimo, Nununun, right?
ぬんぬんも積み上がってますけれども
Nununun is also stacked up, but...
ま、2017年から、8年目？
Well, since 2017, entering our 8th year?
そうだね、になって
That's right. So...
碧ね、数えたんですよ。そらちゃんとの共演を！
Aoi actually counted them! Our co-appearances!
あの、生放送の雑談コラボとかそういうのはなしで
Um, excluding casual chatting stream collabs and stuff like that...
31回！
31 times!
そんなにやってるの！？ うわー！
We've done that many!? Wow!
でも碧調べだから、ちょっと分からないけど、ざっくりそんな感じだった！
But it's based on Aoi's research, so who knows, but roughly around that!
すごーい！
Incredible!
本当にね。配信とか、100万人のお祝いとかも入れたら...
Really, yeah. If we include streams or the 1 million sub celebrations...
もっともっともっと一緒にお仕事させていただいてるなー
We've been working together even more, more, more!
バディだからさ！ 私たちバディだから！
Because we're buddies! We're buddies!
8年目だから、碧の顔もだんだんこう...
Since it's our 8th year, Aoi's face is also slowly...
ぬんぬんと一緒に積み上げてくれないかなー
Won't you stack up together with Nununun?
怖い怖い！ 隣とかでいいから！
Scary, scary! Next to them is fine!
いやすごいね、だって歴史がステージにも散りばめられていて
No, it's amazing. Our history is scattered all over the stage too!
ねー！
Yeah!
すごいでしょ！ めっちゃぬんぬん見てるの。星もあるし
Awesome, right? So many Nununun watching. Stars too!
これ4つ、4つ4つであんきもまでちゃんとあの曲の波調に寄ってこうやってやってるんだよね
These four, 4 and 4, even Ankimo is moving to the song's rhythm like this.
ゆっくりになったりとか、早くなったりとか！ あんきもも頑張ってるのと思って
Slowing down or speeding up! Thinking Ankimo is working hard too.
そう、あんきもめっちゃ頑張ってくれる！
Yeah, Ankimo works really hard for us!
どうですか？ 誕生日の気分
How are you feeling on your birthday?
いや、もうなんかね、さっきまでめっちゃドキドキしてたんだけど、今はこうやってみんなにお祝いされて、めっちゃ嬉しい！
Well, I was super nervous until a moment ago, but now being celebrated by everyone like this, I'm super happy!
みんなたくさんコメントしてってね！
Everyone, please leave lots of comments!
すごいよー！ そらちゃんへの愛がね、そらともさんのそらちゃんへの愛がもう...
It's amazing! The love for Sora-chan, Soratomo's love for Sora-chan is...
あーちゃんとバディだから！
Because I'm buddies with A-chan!
コメントから！ よろしくお願いします！
From the comments! Please send your support!
いっぱいコメントしてよ！
Comment a lot!
いっぱい呟いてよ！ よろしくね！
Tweet a lot! Thanks!
碧もこの後も見守ってるからね！
Aoi will also be watching over you after this!
やったー！
Yay!
また遊ぼうね！
Let me hang out again!
あ、あと新衣装ね！ 楽しみにしてるから！ 遊ぼうね！
Ah, also the new outfit! I'm looking forward to it! Let's hang out!
遊ぼう！ またね！ ありがとう！ 頑張って！
Let's hang out! See you! Thank you! Good luck!
じゃあね！ バイバイ！
See ya! Bye-bye!
なにそれ！ 予想外すぎる！
What was that!? So unexpected!
というわけで、相変わらず仲良しの碧ちゃんでした！
And so, that was Aoi-chan, as close as ever!
それでは続いてのゲストに行きましょう
Now then, let's move on to the next guest!
続いてのゲストは、この方です！
The next guest is this person!
信じてた 信じられた そのすべては 今始まろう
Everything I believed in and was believed for—let it begin now
有象無象の この憂鬱は コンプレックス・イマージュ
This mundane melancholy is a complex image
乾いた風が 追いかける波のように
Like waves chased by a dry wind
突然 背中を押す気がした
I felt as if it suddenly pushed me forward
耳を澄ませば ざわめく六感
If I listen closely, my sixth sense stirs
新しい その場所への 扉を開け放って
Flinging open the door to that new place
切なくて 愛しいほど 思いは時空を超えて
So painful yet dear, my feelings transcend time and space
The girl love ずっと 心はそばにある
The girl, love—my heart is always right beside you
大切な あの陽だまりが 刹那に散りゆく景色
That precious sunlit spot, a scenery scattering in an instant
今すべてを 記憶から 奪い去る前
Before everything is snatched away from memory now
僕は 瞳を 逸らさずに
Without averting my eyes
傷も 涙も 真実も
The scars, the tears, and the truth
あたたかい その雫が 透明なら 力となり
If those warm drops are clear, they become strength,
もしそれが 真紅ならば コンプレックス・イマージュ
if they are crimson, a complex image.
手探りの道から 見出すラビリンス
A labyrinth discovered from a path groped in the dark,
放たれていっても 聞こえる声
even if set free, a voice can still be heard.
目には見えない 確かな Frequency
Invisible to the eye, a certain frequency.
もう二度と 迷わないと 誓える この想い
These feelings that swear to never lose the way again.
遥かなる社の神よ 祈りがもし届くなら
O God of the distant shrine, if my prayer reaches you...
すべての 慈愛に和み 微笑みを
soften in all affection, and bring a smile.
この迷いは もう何もなく 導く光のままに
With this hesitation now long gone, guided by the light...
今 すべての 悲しみを 捨てて
Now, casting away all sadness...
僕は 瞳を そらさずに
I will not avert my eyes...
傷も 涙も 真実も
from the wounds, the tears, and the truth.
切なくて 愛しいほど 思いは時空を超えて
So painful yet beloved, these thoughts transcend space and time.
Together 遠く 心はそばにある
Together, far away, our hearts are side by side.
大切な あの陽だまりが 切なに散りゆく景色
That precious sunny spot, a scene scattering sorrowfully.
今 すべての 力を 与えたまえ
Now grant me all your strength.
僕は 瞳を そらさずに
I will not avert my eyes...
傷も 涙も 真実も
from the wounds, the tears, and the truth.
はい！聴いていただいたのは『コンプレックス・イマージュ』でした！
Yes! That was "COMPLEX IMAGE"!
そして、ゲストに来ていただきました、彩音さんです！
And joining us as a guest, it's Ayane-san!
彩音でーす！
I'm Ayane!
そらともの皆さん、はじめまして！彩音です！
Nice to meet all of you Soratomo! I'm Ayane!
今日は来ていただいて、本当に本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so very much for coming today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
嬉しすぎて、もうテンションが上がってしまっていますが...
I'm so happy, my excitement is through the roof, but...
私もです！
Me too!
あ、本当ですか！ありがとうございます！
Oh, really? Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
今回彩音さんに来ていただいたのは、私、恐れ多くも『コンプレックス・イマージュ』をカバーさせていただきまして...
The reason I invited Ayane-san today is that I humbly had the honor of covering "COMPLEX IMAGE"...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
それに反応していただいたのがとても嬉しくて...
And I was so happy that you responded to it...
ぜひぜひコラボで歌わせていただけたら嬉しいなと思って、お呼びいたしました！
So I invited you, hoping we could perform a collaboration duet together!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
来てくださると思ってなくて、今ドキドキが止まらないんですけど...
I didn't think you'd actually come, so my heart won't stop pounding right now...
私もです！今すごい心拍数が上がってます！
Me too! My heart rate is crazy high right now!
本当に本当に素敵な歌声で、私ずっとこうやって聴いてようかなって途中から思っちゃいました！
You have such a wonderful voice that halfway through I thought about just standing here listening!
いやいや！一緒に歌っていただいてありがとうございました！
Oh no, no! Thank you so much for singing with me!
ライブでこういう風に一緒に歌えるとは思ってなかったんですけど...
I never imagined we'd be able to sing together at a live show like this...
どうでしょう、こういう大きいステージで一緒に歌うのは...
How was it to sing together on such a big stage?
嬉しいです！あの、そらさんは...
I'm so happy! Um, Sora-san...
横浜アリーナが目標なんですよね？
Yokohama Arena is your goal, right?
はい！はい！そうです！
Yes! Yes! That's right!
いつかその夢が叶った時に、ご一緒出来たら嬉しいです！
Someday when that dream comes true, I'd be delighted to perform with you!
え！いいんですか！？いいんですか！？
Eh?! Really?! Is that okay?!
はい！すごーく楽しみにしてます！
Yes! I'll be really looking forward to it!
また歌ってくれるんですか！？
Will you sing with me again?!
はい、もちろん
Yes, of course!
です。
I'd love to!
とっても嬉しいです！
I'm so happy!
もう、本当に、ずっとずっと聴いていた曲で...
Seriously, it's a song I've listened to forever...
他の曲も、めちゃくちゃ聴いているので...
And I listen to your other songs all the time, so...
嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
I'm so glad. Thank you so much.
本当に、大好きな方に、こうやって生誕祭に来ていただけて、もう私、感謝でいっぱいです！
Having someone I love so much come to my birthday celebration, I'm just full of gratitude!
今後ともよろしくおね... / 今後ともぜひよろしくね...
I look forward to working with you again... / Likewise!
また...なんかコラボとか出来たら、とっても嬉しいなと思います！
Also, if we could collaborate again, I'd be so happy!
ぜひ！よろしくお願いします！ / よろしくお願いし...
Definitely! I look forward to it! / Looking forward...
まーす！
...to it!
改めまして、そらさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, Sora-san, happy birthday!
ありがとうございまーす！
Thank you so much!
と言うことで、
So then...
本日は彩音さんに来ていただきました！
...today we were joined by Ayane-san!
本当に、本当に、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so, so much!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
緊張した〜！
I was so nervous!
緊張したよ〜！
I was so nervous, you know!
みんなにも緊張が伝わってたよね？
I bet my nervousness came through to everyone, right?
緊張で上手く言えない...
I'm so nervous I can't even speak properly...
トレンド1位になったの！？
Did we reach #1 on trending?!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
と言う訳で、あの...
So anyway, um...
お誕生日配信も...
...this birthday stream...
終盤に近づいてきたんですけども、
...is coming close to the end, but...
えーっと...
...um...
いや...感無量すぎて...
...I'm just so overwhelmed with emotion...
何も言えない...
...I don't know what to say...
でも！
But!
まだ！まだまだ！
There's still, still more to come!
先があるよね！
There's still more ahead, right?!
みんな！
Everyone!
新衣装、見たいよね！？
You want to see my new outfit, right?!
という訳で、新衣装お披露目の時間だよー！
So, it's time to reveal the new outfit!
みんな、準備はいいー？
Everyone, are you ready?!
いくよー！せーの！
Here we go! Ready, set!
へへっ
Hehe!
へへへっ
Hehehe!
ちらっ、ちらっ、見えた見えた
Peek! Peek! I saw it, I saw it!
イエーイ！
Yay!
うわ〜！
Whoa!
どう？ちょっと見えた？ちょっと見えた？
How is it? Could you see a bit? Could you see a bit?
ちょっと見えたよねー！
You could see a little bit, right?!
手しか見えない...きゃっ！
I can only see my hand... Eek!
さあ！あ、おめでとうみんなありがとう！
Alright! Ah, happy birthday, thank you everyone!
みんな、「見たい」って言って！
Everyone, say "I want to see it!"
せーの！
Ready, set!
もっともっと！「見たい見たい」！
More, more! "We wanna see it, we wanna see it!"
聞こえないぞ〜！「見たい」！
I can't hear you! "We wanna see it!"
あ、素晴らしいみんな！
Ah, wonderful, everyone!
では行きますよ！
Alright, here we go!
3, 2, 1, オープン！
3, 2, 1, OPEN!
はい！ということでどうかな？今回の新衣装です！
Alright! What do you think? Here is my new outfit!
なんとね、これね、あの、テーマが...
Actually, the theme for this...
書いただけてて...
...was written down for me...
何だと思う？テーマ。
What do you think the theme is?
読みますね。「モノトーン絶対領域パンツ」。
I'll read it: "Monotone Absolute Territory Pants".
どういうことー！？どういうことー！？
What does that even mean?! What does that mean?!
というわけで今回はですね、ちょっとショートヘアに憧れちゃいまして...
So this time, I really wanted to try short hair...
私、ちょっとショートヘアのウィッグを...
...so I got myself a short hair wig!
手に入れちゃいました！
I got one!
どうー？ショートヘア。
How is it? Short hair!
初めてだからちょっと緊張してるんだけど、似合うかな？似合うかな？
It's my first time, so I'm a bit nervous. Does it suit me? Does it suit me?
どういうこと？なんてテーマだ。多分これが絶対領域ってことなんじゃないかな？
What does it mean? What a theme! Maybe this part is the absolute territory?
でね、他にも色んなものがあるんですけど...
And, there are other parts to it too, but...
それは、配信後のアフターライブ、メンバー限定で見せちゃおうかなって思ってるから...
I'm thinking of showing them during the member-exclusive after-live stream after this!
ぜひ、そっちも見たいなって人は、メン限に来てくれると嬉しいよ！
So if you'd like to see that too, I'd be super happy if you joined the members stream!
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
向いてない
I'm not cut out for this...
向いてないない 今すぐやめてしまうか
Not cut out, not at all, should I just quit right now?
そりゃないない いつになれば僕は
That can't be it, when will I finally...
主役になれるのかな
become the main character, I wonder?
足りなくなっては高笑ったり
When coming up short, laughing maniacally...
増えた荷物数えては泣いたり
Counting my growing burdens and crying...
期待するほどでもなくガッカリ
Disappointed because it wasn't even worth expecting...
詰めることすらできず揉んだり
Struggling without even being able to close the distance...
燦然と輝く街の明かり
The brilliantly glittering lights of the city...
散々だって言わん通り素通り
Passing right by, as if saying it was terrible...
始めるなら今 そうだな またやろう
"If I'm starting, it's now", yeah, let me try again!
これじゃないない あまりに悪いようだ
This isn't it, it seems way too bad.
向いてないない 今すぐやめてしまえば
Not cut out for it, if I just quit right now...
でも何万回と繰り返した
But even after repeating it tens of thousands of times...
明日に期待してしまうか
Will I end up placing my hopes on tomorrow?
明け方の妄想 既定の逃避行 勘違いの英雄ごっこ
Early morning delusions, a routine escape, playing a misunderstood hero...
もう渋滞してんだ どうしようもこうしようもないような
It's already congested, with no way to handle it or do anything about it.
あの頃は確かにあったんだ
Back then, it definitely existed.
描き出したものがあったんだ
There was something I depicted.
いつの間にやら僕は
Somewhere along the line, I...
誰かが突然に始まった
Suddenly started with someone...
デタラメなシナリオの上で
On top of a ridiculous scenario...
何かを演じるの 誰かを演じるの
Am I acting something? Am I acting someone?
そんなわけがないだろう
That can't possibly be true!
まだこれじゃない まだここじゃないない
This isn't it yet, this isn't the place yet!
終わりじゃないから
Because this isn't the end!
向いてないない なら書き換えてしまえよ
Not cut out for it? Then just rewrite it!
これじゃないない いつもいつでもきっと
This isn't it, always, anytime, surely...
主役は僕だけだろう
The star can only be me!
いつの日かバイバイ 終わりは来るから
Someday, bye-bye, because the end will come...
拍手喝采 笑顔で願ったアンコール
Applause and cheers, an encore requested with smiles!
描いた未来はどこにあった
Where was the future I drew?
思うままに好き放題に
As I please, doing whatever I like...
色がそうさ
This is it!
どん底から駆け上がった
Rising up from rock bottom...
映画のようなストーリー
A story just like a movie!
はい！ということで最後のゲストは
All right! So, our last guests are...
はじめちゃんがらでんちゃんの
Hajime-chan and Raden-chan...
らではじめコンビ！
The Rade-Haji duo!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ぼんぼんぼん！ほららじまちかりべっとりごっちょん ばんちょ！轟はじめっちょ！
Bon bon bon! Todoroki Hajime-cho!
はい！
Yes!
噛んだ...
I stumbled on my words...
全然見えない！
I couldn't read that at all!
儒烏風亭らでんでございます！
I'm Juufuutei Raden!
イエーイ！
Yay!
そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
そして新衣装！
And your new outfit!
かわいいー！
So cute!
え、ぜひちょっとスクショなど撮りたいなっちゃ思うんですけど...
Um, I'd definitely like to take some screenshots...
あ、じゃあポーズ...
Ah, then poses...
手持ちカメラ借りて...
Borrowing a handheld camera...
なんて？なんでそら先輩が撮られる方...
Wait, why? Why is Sora-senpai the one taking the picture...
かわいいなー
So cute~
じゃあはじめからポーズ指定なんか言っちゃったり
Okay, Hajime, why don't you suggest a pose first?
そら先輩のせ、セクシーポーズ！
Sora-senpai's, s-sexy pose!
このラインが良いですね！このラインが！
This curve is great! This line right here!
シンプルな衣装だからこそ映えるね！
Because it's a simple outfit, it really stands out!
この絶対領域の部分とかも...
This absolute territory section too...
すごい！なんかチョコ...なんだろ、ベルトみたいな感じになってて めっちゃめちゃ素敵！
Awesome! It's like a belt design, it looks super lovely!
素敵やん！
It's so nice!
え、じゃあちょっとらでんからも！見返り美人のポーズなんて頼んでもいいですか？
Well then, from Raden too! May I request a "Beauty Looking Back" pose?
お、頼んだ！かわいいー！
Oh, requested! So cute~!
これには菱川師宣様もニッコリですよ！
Even Hishikawa Moronobu would smile at this!
見返り美人の人か！
Ah, the artist behind "Beauty Looking Back"!
みんなスクショできた？
Everyone, did you get your screenshots?
なんか髪型も...
Also, the hairstyle...
脇が見えちゃう！
You can see her armpits!
そら先輩の脇がー！
Sora-senpai's armpits!
めっちゃ良いー！
So good~!
え、じゃあ3人でも撮りたい！
Eh, then I want to take a photo of all 3 of us!
いいですか？
Is that okay?
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
髪型、ショート同士！
Short hair duo!
おそろい！
Matching!
なんかいいな！
I really like this!
服装モノトーンだし！
The outfit is monotone too!
一人だけ季節感バグった人が...
One person's sense of season is totally bugged...
そんなことない！そんなことない！
That's not true! That's not true!
あ、ちょうどいい。
Ah, it's just right.
ちょうどいい。
Just right.
いや～
Well...
ふたりと一緒に歌えて、とっても嬉しかったし、
I was super happy to sing together with you two,
これからも仲良くしてほしいよ！
and I hope we continue to get along well!
こちらこそ！よろしくお願いします！
Likewise! Nice to work with you!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
皆様お邪魔しましたー！ありがとうございました！
Sorry for barging in, everyone! Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
我々は...では、また皆さん...
We shall... Well then, everyone...
あーっ！
Ah!
その去り方は斬新すぎる...
That way of leaving is way too novel...
あんきもの中に消えていっちゃったよ...
They disappeared into Ankimo...
ということで、ライブも終盤に近づいてきましたが、最後まで盛り上がっていきましょう！
So, the live concert is nearing its end, but let's keep the hype going until the very end!
次の曲を聴いてください。『UNDEAD』
Please listen to the next song: "UNDEAD".
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
UNHAPPY? O, child of man in doubt
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
UNLUCKY? Even those who aren't human
BE HAPPY! 怠まず目指せよ 生きているんだし
BE HAPPY! Keep aiming without slacking, since you're alive after all
目を逸らした過去も 退屈な未来も
Both the past you turned away from and the boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ 古今東西 ピースピース
Counseling, oh my, all times and places, peace, peace
ねぇ 何だかどうして 戦ってるような そんな気がするの
Hey, why does it feel like I'm somehow fighting?
触れられない 触れたくもない
I can't touch it, I don't even want to touch it
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分と
With my past self, self, self, self
もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Facing off against a transparent ghost that's long been dead
幼気で痛い記憶の奥
Deep within childish, painful memories
残念？ もう居ないのに
A shame? Even though they're no longer here
あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Huh? You prefer that one? How ironic
透かされているのは現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my current self?
ナンセンス
Nonsense
消えないレッテル
A label that won't disappear
YES! 要はコンプレックス
YES! In short, a complex
取り憑かれているみたい
It's like being possessed
巻き付いたまま
Clinging around me
まだ離れない
It still won't let go
在りし日の自分
My self from those bygone days
UNDEAD 死んじゃいない
UNDEAD, not dead yet
お前と前の連鎖
The continuous chain of you and the past
受けてることとは変わり続けること
Receiving it means continuing to change
不幸に甘んじて満足するなよ
Don't settle for misfortune and be satisfied
幸せになろうとしたいんだよ 今日だ
I want to try to be happy, starting today
この世 この世は ピッカピカ ファンタジー
This world, this world is a sparkling fantasy
次は鬼化けるか 厄介化けるか
Will I turn into a demon next, or turn into trouble?
出会って出会って やっと始まる物語が
Meeting and meeting, a story that finally begins
人型だけの化け物が可愛いピースピース
A monster merely shaped like a human, cute peace peace
何だかどうして みんな良い人なんぞなんだの
Why is everyone somehow a good person or something?
容赦なきな
So relentless
ようなく気がして
I feel like that
もう随分行ってる 実感と正論で食傷
Going pretty far now, fed up with reality and sound logic
素敵なって気事の気配もない
No sign of anything wonderful happening
さあね
Who knows
積んだ経験値が警戒化された神話と退屈な進化
Accumulated experience points turned into a guarded myth and boring evolution
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて
Getting bored, getting used to it
辿っていくガイダンス
Following the guidance
増えるコンプライアンス
Increasing compliance
試されているみたい
Feels like being tested
追従して
Following along
あれもこれもどれも同じ味がする
That, this, and that all taste the same
UNDEAD 死んじゃいない
UNDEAD, not dead yet
お前と前の連鎖
The continuous chain of you and the past
いつの一番も過去も見ない もう今にあるんだ
Not looking at the peak or the past anymore, it's in the present now
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ 目指せハッピーエンド
Fulfill being alive with honesty, aim for a happy ending
死んじゃいない
Not dead yet
お前に似てるんだ
I resemble you
幸せを諦めてスマイルな人で居あれ
Stay as someone smiling, having given up on happiness
ただ苦しみに慣れて冴えているだけじゃん
Just getting used to suffering and staying sharp, that's all
死んでるのと同義
It's synonymous with being dead
屍のUNDEAD
The corpse's UNDEAD
奇異にならざる者も
Even those who don't become strange
絶えず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Keep aiming endlessly, you're alive, right?
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Drowning in unhappiness or becoming happy
そう全部全部 お前だ
Yes, all of it, all of it is you
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
All times and places, absolutely everything, all of creation, peace, peace
人となる心
A heart that becomes human
憎むも礼儀と
Hating as a courtesy
行けるこの化け物の ばかりの物語
A story full of monsters that can go on
はい！ということで！『UNDEAD』歌いました！
Yes! And with that, I sang "UNDEAD"!
今回も振付を作っていただいて、頑張って歌いましたが、みんなどうだったかな？
We had the choreography made for us again, and I sang my heart out, how was it everyone?
どうだったかな？いい感じだったかな？
How was it? Was it feeling good?
ちょっとね、細かくて難しかったんですけど、でも楽しく歌えたし、みんなが見てくれててとっても嬉しいです！
It was a bit detailed and tricky, but I had fun singing it, and I'm super happy everyone watched!
というわけで、まだ最後にお披露目はあるんですが、
So then, we still have one final reveal left, but...
その前にお知らせが2つあります！
before that, I have two announcements!
まずはこちら！
First, this!
ときのそら 誕生日記念2025グッズです！
Tokino Sora Birthday Commemorative 2025 Merchandise!
コメントー！
Comments!
言っていってくれてる気がする！
I feel like you guys are telling me!
順番に紹介していくよ！
I'll introduce them one by one!
まずは...こちら！
First off... this!
「夢のそらばワンマン」ファブリックポスター！
"Yume no Sora ba One-Man" Fabric Poster!
私がダンスしてるワンシーンを切り取った、布製のファブリックポスターです。
It's a fabric poster capturing a scene of me dancing.
紙のポスターと違って折れたりする心配もないですし...
Unlike paper posters, you don't have to worry about creasing...
長く飾ってくれるかなということで...
so you can display it for a long time...
お部屋のサイズに合わせてね、折りたたんだりして飾ることもできると思うので...
and depending on your room's space, you can fold it to display it...
ぜひぜひみんな、部屋に飾ってね！
so please display it in your room, everyone!
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
そらとおそろい2Wayネックレス！
Sora Matching 2Way Necklace!
ということで、今回の新衣装でもつけてるネックレスのおそろっちが作りたいなと思って...
So, I wanted to create a matching version of the necklace I'm wearing with this new outfit...
おそろっちのものを用意しました。
and prepared this matching item.
ただね、「ネックレスはしないよ」って人のために...
However, for people who don't wear necklaces...
チャーム部分を取り外しすることができる2Way仕様になっていまして...
it comes in a 2-way design where you can detach the charm section...
バッグとかにワンポイントでつけて...
so you can attach it to a bag as an accent...
一緒におそろっちってできるようにしました。
and match with me that way too!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
そらのバンダナハンカチ！
Sora's Bandana Handkerchief!
お揃い柄のハンカチ。
A handkerchief with a matching pattern.
今回はね、みんなとおそろっちっていうのをテーマに作ってみました。
This time, I made items with the theme of "matching with everyone".
シンプルなデザインなので日常でも使えますし...
It's a simple design, so you can use it every day...
でもちょっとロゴも入ってるのでとっても可愛いかなと思います。
and with the small logo, I think it's super cute.
シンプルで、いつも持ち歩きやすく、でもお揃いにもできる。
It's simple, easy to carry around, but still lets us match.
ちょっとね、みんなバンダナはしないかなと思ってハンカチにしてみました。
I thought maybe not everyone wears bandanas, so I made it a handkerchief.
みんなで私を持ち歩いてね！
Carry me around with you, everyone!
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
いつも一緒おでかけぬいバッグ！
"Always Together Outing Plush Bag"!
こちらはパーカー衣装の私が乗ったぬんぬん型のポーチを...
This is a Nun-Nun-shaped pouch featuring me in my hoodie outfit...
開けるとあんときも柄のバッグが出てくるぬいバッグということで...
and when you open it, an Ankimon-patterned plush bag comes out...
ぬいぐるみキーホルダーの感覚でこう一緒に歩くこととか...
You can carry it around like a plush keychain...
カバンにつける痛バッグみたいに作ることもできるし...
or use it like an ita-bag on your tote...
持ち運べるし...
It's portable...
なんかグッズとか買いすぎちゃったってときに「入らないな」ってときに...
and if you buy too much merch and think "it won't fit..."
ちょっと出して使えたりもすると思うので...
you can pull it out and use it as an extra bag!
ぜひぜひ、これはね、ずっと出してみたかったグッズなので...
So please do! This is an item I've wanted to make for a long time...
皆さん見てもらえると嬉しいです！
I'd be really happy if you check it out!
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, this!
ボイス！
Voice Pack!
シチュエーションボイス「ライブの後で」
Situation Voice "After the Concert"
ちょっとお茶目な私とこれからに向けて意気込みを語るかっこいい私の両方が楽しめるボイスです。
It's a voice pack where you can enjoy both a playful side of me and a cool side sharing my future goals.
そして今回はフルセットの特典が2つあるよ！
And this time, there are two full set purchase bonuses!
まずはこちら！
First is this!
ときのそら直筆サイン＋箔押し複製メッセージ！
Tokino Sora Autograph + Foil-Stamped Message!
今回はですね、いつもなんですけど数量限定なしでやるので...
This time, as always, we're doing it with NO limited quantity!
ぜひ皆さん...たくさんたくさんサイン書かせてください。
So please... let me sign a whole lot for everyone!
心を込めて全部書くから、ぜひぜひ...
I'll sign every single one with all my heart, so please...
いっぱい応募してね！
apply a lot!
そしてもう1つの特典はこちら！
And the other bonus is this!
昨年9月から販売されたホロライブ公式カードゲームで...
A promo card usable in the Hololive Official Card Game...
使用できるPRカードが1枚つきます！
...which launched last September!
フルセットを購入した人だけの特別な推しホロメンカードです。
It's a special "Oshi Holomen Card" exclusively for full set buyers.
まだ遊んだことないよって人...
For those who haven't played yet...
ホロライブ公式カードゲームのホームページやカードの詳細や遊び方を確認できるからぜひチェックしてね！
you can check the official site to learn about card details and how to play!
これでみんな買ってくれるだろうな...
I hope everyone buys it with this...
買ってくれよ〜！
Please buy it~!
ということで、以上誕生日グッズでした！みんなよろしくね！
And with that, that's all for the birthday merch! Thanks everyone!
そして2つ目のお知らせは...
And the second announcement is...
なんと...
What's this...?!
昨日...今日なのかな？0時に...
Yesterday... or was it today at midnight...
デジタル配信が始まりました...
digital streaming began for...
「Swallow Tail」の...ミュージックビデオ！なんと...
"Swallow Tail"... music video! Surprisingly...
この後...プレミアム公開！
it will premiere... right after this!
みんな...みんなに感謝の気持ちを込めてMVを...
Everyone... I prepared an MV with all my gratitude for you...
用意しておきました！
I prepared it!
ぜひぜひ皆さんもMVでも私の曲聞いてください！
So please listen to my song with the MV as well!
これが嬉しい告知だよ〜
This is my happy announcement~!
こちら、曲のテーマというか爽やかな感じで...
This song has a refreshing feel as its theme...
みんなへの感謝の気持ちを込めつつ、ちょっと切ない歌詞もあったりするので...
expressing my gratitude to everyone, while also having some poignant lyrics...
とても...そうなんですよ、MV発表がありました！
So... yes, that's right! The MV announcement!
この後21時15分からの予定なんですけどすごくギリギリかもしれない...
It's scheduled for 21:15 after this, but time might be really tight...
ええ...明言は21時半からになります！
To be safe, let's say it starts at 21:30!
よろしくお願いします！
Please check it out!
というわけで...
So...
その曲...最後に聞きたくない？
don't you want to hear that song at the end?
初めて生で歌います！
I'll sing it live for the first time!
この曲で締めたいと思います。
I'd like to close out with this song.
聞いてください。「Swallow Tail」
Please listen: "Swallow Tail".
澄み渡る青はいつも 始まりを強く照らすから
The clear blue sky always brightly illuminates the beginning,
本当は震えている 手足が隠せないよ
so I can't hide my hands and feet that are actually trembling.
物語の先はどう？ 君なら何色で描く？
How does the story go from here? What color would you draw it in?
むせび泣いた日のこと やめられなかった日のことを
The days I choked back tears, the days I couldn't stop...
燕みたいに早く 止められないハイ
Fast like a swallow, an unstoppable high,
もう何にもいらないから 忘れさせないから どこまでも遠くへと
I don't need anything else anymore, I won't let you forget, going further and further away...
このまま手を繋いで 向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
Holding hands like this, letting tears swim into the headwind,
淡い闇を越えて 歪な翼で踊ろう
crossing the pale darkness, let us dance with distorted wings,
無限の夏の空へ
towards the infinite summer sky.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
失くした鍵は見つかった 燃えるゴミの日に出しちゃった
The lost key was found... and thrown out on burnable trash day.
いつの間にか傷つけた 君のスペシャルな夢の船
Without realizing it, I hurt your special ship of dreams.
子供みたいに青く 願えたらいいのに
If only I could wish so naively like a child,
気が付けば檻の中で
before I knew it, I was inside a cage.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
胸の隅で痛んで 泣くのは きっと大事なものだから
The aching and crying in the corner of my heart is surely because it's something precious.
間違っても 彷徨っても 離さないでいよう
Even if I make mistakes, even if I wander, let's not let go.
空の果て 群青のその先を見つめて
Looking beyond the end of the sky, beyond the deep blue,
飛びたいの この命懸けて
I want to fly, risking this life of mine.
もう何にもいらないから 忘れさせないから どこまでも遠くへと
I don't need anything else anymore, I won't let you forget, going further and further away...
ありのまま紡いで 向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
Weaving things as they are, letting tears swim into the headwind,
淡い闇を越えて 歪な翼でいよう
crossing the pale darkness, let's keep our distorted wings.
行こう 無限の夏の空へ
Let's go towards the infinite summer sky.
今日観に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to watch today!
ソロ配信もとっても楽しかったし
My solo stream was super fun too,
ショートヘアも嬉しいぞ！
and I'm so happy with this short hair!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you so much!
ファンクラブの2次配信も 限定だけど、よかったら来てね！
The fan club secondary stream is limited too, but please come if you can!
バイバイ！
Bye-bye!